### Resume

View the Project on GitHub at https://github.com/

Click here to view the most recent version of my portfolio. Click here to download the most recent pdf file.

# Myles J. Johnson-Gray

mjayegray@gmail.com | 302-670-9580

### **Education**

- University of Delaware (Aug 2015-May 2017)
  - Master of Science in Computer Science
  - o GPA: 3.2
- Delaware State University (Aug 2011-May 2015)
  - Bachelor of Science in Computer Science; Magna Cum Laude
  - GPA: 3.5

## Summary

Experienced engineering professional with knowledge of scripting and object-oriented programming, agile and scrum practices, version control, database management, and software testing. Familiarity with Windows, Unix, and Linux operating systems. Offering strong teamwork and communication skills, as well as a determined attitude, translating to high levels of productivity. Demonstrated ability to utilize strong critical thinking skills, along with broad savvy of technology, computers, and mathematics.

Specific interests include subjects in the following areas: artificial intelligence, data mining, and user interface design.

## **Technical Skills**

### **Programming Languages**

Knowledge of various programming languages including: C++, Java, Python, HTML, Javascript, ASP, Visual Basic, Perl, Ruby, PHP, Bash, Ada, ML, Prolog, and SQL.

#### **Mathematics**

Strong skills in mathematics including: basic arithmetic, algebra, calculus, probability, statistics, trigonometry, discrete mathematics, linear algebra, and theory of computation.

## Systems/Software:

Familiarity with various software: Microsoft Office, Wireshark, SSH, VirtualBox, Eclipse, PyCharm, GitHub, Rational Clearcase, JIRA Software, Confluence, Froglogic Squish, SmartBear Collaborator, OpenGL, and XAMMP.

## **Relevant Experience**

#### **Raytheon Technologies - Software Engineer II**

### Lawrence, Massachusetts, USA (May 2018 - Present)

- Developed, facilitated the delivery of, and performed regression/integration testing on maintenance software (Ada/C++) for Patriot Missle System.
- Produced in-house scripting and front end tools (Python, Javascript, ASP, PHP) to improve development and testing efficiency of engineering teams.
- Responsible for introducing DevSecOps and agile softwares (JIRA, Confluence, Collaborator, GitHub) and concepts to outdated engineering product groups.
- Secret Clearance from U.S. Department of Defense

#### Delaware State University - Undergraduate Researcher

#### Dover, Delaware, USA (Feb 2012 - May 2015)

- Assisted in the software development of NeRvolver, a computational intelligence-based system (using evolutionary algorithms and fuzzy logic) for automated construction, analysis, and tuning of neuronal models.
- Implemented the NSGA-2 and END\_VEGA algorithms in C++, and performed an empirical algorithm analysis on both algorithms applied to neuronal modeling.
- Implemented statistical functions for analysis of neuronal data.
- Contributed in a lab research team: committed code to a code base, participated in lab meetings, and orally presented our work at several conferences.

#### National Institute of Health - International Summer Research Intern

#### Ningbo University, Ningbo, China (May 2012 - July 2012)

- Participated in courses covering knowledge of various data mining techniques, including clustering, classification methods, and decision trees.
- Developed decision trees, predicting several NBA player shot selections and results based on a number of in-game critieria. Prepared an oral and poster presentation of my work at a local symposium.

#### **Summer Research Intern**

#### Clemson University, South Carolina, USA (May 2014 - July 2014)

- Developed a graph ontology based system for keyword extraction of biomedical publications in Java. Prepared an oral and poster presentation for a local symposium.
- Participated in a number of courses covering SSH, operating systems, and object-oriented programming fundamentals.

## **Github Repositories**

Each bullet below contains a hyperlink mapping to the respective repository location.

• Constructed a character prediction system using bigrams to generate predictions for a dynamic AAC keyboard.

- Implemented shading, reflection/refraction, bump mapping, model loading, and flocking schemas in graphics projects using OpenGL.
- Created a Perl program to simulate the mutation and alignment of amino acid sequences using a PAM matrix.
- Built and tested a decision tree class on Wisconsin breast cancer data.
- Developed a Forward Chaining Knowledge Base of Restaurants for Main Street (Newark, Delaware).
- Designed a stock market QA system using sentiment analysis.
- Produced a system that uses Hidden Markov Models through viterbi training to find the most likely path for given genome sequences.

### **AUTHORED PUBLICATIONS**

- "Hybridization of multi-objective evolutionary algorithms and fuzzy control for automated construction, tuning, and analysis of neuronal models" peer-reviewed abstract, Patel P., Johnson-Gray M., Forren E., Malik A., and Smolinski T.G., BMC Neuroscience 14(Suppl 1):P369, 2013.
- "NeRvolver: a computational intelligence-based system for automated construction, tuning, and analysis of neuronal models" peer-reviewed abstract, Forren E., Johnson-Gray M., Patel P., and Smolinski T.G., BMC Neuroscience 13(Suppl 1):P36, 2012.

### **SPEAKING ENGAGEMENTS**

- Computational Neuroscience (CNS) Conference (Atlanta 2012, Paris 2013)
- Annual Biomedical Research Conference for Minority Students (ABRCMS) (San Jose 2012, Nashville 2013, San Antonio 2014)
- Emerging Researchers National (ERN) Conference (Washington D.C 2014)

Project maintained by **gitmyles**Hosted on GitHub Pages — Theme by **orderedlist**